Guide to the Carol R. Lubin papers, 1960-1981
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Carol R. Lubin papers
1960-1981
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Carol Riegelman Lubin, 1909-2005
C0105
4 linear ft.; 8 boxes
The Carol R. Lubin papers is a collection of papers pertaining to Lubin's work as a consultant for social planning in Reston, Virginia. The collection contains correspondence, reports, and plans as well as papers from international communities in Israel, Poland and Great Britain.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Carol R. Lubin in August of 1995.
Biographical Information
Carol Riegelman Lubin was born on September 23, 1909. She graduated from Smith College in 1930 and received a M.A. and Ph.D. from Columbia University in public law. She married Isador Lubin, an economist who worked closely with President Franklin D. Roosevelt on the New Deal, and they had two daughters. Lubin was associated professionally with the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, the International Labor Organization, Rutgers University, the New York Urban Coalition and the United Neighborhood Houses.
Lubin joined the Reston staff in September of 1961 in order to direct the community planning for the city in the areas of educational, cultural, recreational, social, and religious activities. As the consultant for social planning she developed conferences with social scientists, religious leaders, architects, foundation representatives, government officials, developers of the British new towns and community leaders in various voluntary agencies. Carol Lubin died on July 26, 2005.
Scope and Content
The Carol R. Lubin papers is a collection of papers pertaining to Dr. Lubin's work as a consultant for social planning in Reston, Virginia. The collection contains correspondence, reports, plans and papers from international communities in Israel, Poland and Great Britain.
Series one is titled correspondence. The series contains the correspondence to and from Carol R. Lubin. The correspondence pertains to Reston activities, committees, school, foundation for community programs, nature center and various other organizations. The series is dated from 1962 to 1969 and is contained in box 1.
Series two is titled reports and plans. The series contains the reports and plans for different projects in Reston. Some of the projects include, child care, education, low income housing and papers from the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). The series is dated from 1961 to 1969 and is contained in boxes 1-3.
Series three is titled international. The papers in this series are from different planned communities around the world. Most of the papers relate to Israel with additional information from Poland, Great Britain and Japan. The series is dated from 1965 to 1971 and is contained in boxes 3-5.
Series four is titled booklets. The information in this series includes office workbooks, Reston manual, promotional pamphlets and other information. The series is dated from 1960 to 1981 and is contained in boxes 5-6.
Series five is titled general information. The papers cover a variety of topics related to Dr. Lubin's career in Reston. Among the papers are addresses, maps, notes, press releases, newspaper articles and other papers. The series is dated from 1962 to 1971 and is contained in boxes 6-7.
Series six is titled oversize. The series is small and contains information related to Israel. Included in the series are drawings of different planned communities and a book about Israeli development. The series is dated from 1967 to 1968 and is contained in box 8.
Arrangement
Organized into six series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1962-1969 (Boxes 1)
Series 2: Reports and Plans, 1961-1969 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 3: International, 1965-1976 (Boxes 3-5)
Series 4: Booklets, 1960-1981 (Boxes 5-6)
Series 5: General Information, 1962-1971 (Boxes 6-7)
Series 6: Oversize, 1967-1968 (Boxes 8)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds many other collections on the history and development of Reston, Virginia, as well as other collections that document United States and international planned communities.
Index Terms
Persons:
Lubin, Carol Riegelman.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.).
Subjects:
Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1962-1969; (1 box)
  The series contains the correspondence to and from Carol R. Lubin. The correspondence pertains to Reston activities, committees, school, foundation for community programs, nature center and various other organizations.
  - American Organization for Rehabilitation through Training (O.R.T.) Federation, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    444.12
  - Correspondence: Biographical Material, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    444.13
  - Day Care, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    444.14
    - Letter: Eleanor M. Hosley to Carol R. Lubin, November 29, 1967; 1.
  - Employee Benefits, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    444.16
  - Federal Aid to Reston, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    444.17
  - Ford Foundation Presentation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    444.18
    - Letter: Marshall Kaplan to Carol R. Lubin, July 5, 1966; 1.
    - Reston Proposal Part I: Anonymous, ca. 1965; 2.
  - Ford Foundation Presentation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    444.19
    - Memorandum: Joan Wofford to Robert Simon, Carol Lubin, Bernie Norwitch, and Jane Wilhelm, March 24, 1966; 1.
    - Reston Proposal Part II: Anonymous, ca. 1965; 2.
  - From: David Best, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gulf Investment in Reston, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    445.1
    - Gulf Investment in Reston (Memo), May 5, 1967; 1.
  - Personal, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    446.9
  - Pop Quiz for Reston Salesmen, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    447.9
    - Answers to Pop Quiz for Reston Salesman, October 28,1966; 1.
  - Presentation to Magazine and Industrial Officials, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    447.11
  - Reston Activities/Commitments, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    446.8
  - Reston Virginia Foundation for Community Programs, Incorporated, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    448.14
    - Letter: T. Keith Glennan and Richard G. Henniger, September 1, 1967; 1.
    - Memo: Linsenmeyer to Board of Trustees of Reston, VA Foundation for Community Programs, Inc., November 14, 1967; 2.
    - Memo: Reston Foundation for Community Programs, Inc., November 1967; 3.
  - Reston School, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    448.6
  - The Nature Center-Reston, Virginia, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    446.12
    - The Nature Center, Reston Virginia, November 8, 1967; 1.
  - Weekly Legislative Digest, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Zukowsky Manuscript, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    448.19
- Series 2: Reports and Plans, 1961-1696; (2 boxes)
  The series contains the reports and plans for different projects in Reston. Some of the projects include, child care, education, low income housing and papers from the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).
  - A Survey of Town House Buyers and Prospects-Reston, Virginia, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    448.17
  - Architectural Development Proposal, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    444.5
    - Architectural Development Proposal, February 18, 1966; 1.
    - Report: Anonymous, Architectural Development Proposal, February 18, 1966; 2.
  - Architectural Drawings-Whittlesey and Conklin, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    444.6
  - Child Care and Working Mothers, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Community and Public Relations Division-May Monthly Report, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    444.11
  - Education in Media, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
    444.15
    - Project Proposal: Anonymous, "Education in Media", ca. 1965; 1.
  - Elementary School, Intermediate School-Reston, Virginia, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    448.16
  - First Exhibition-Reston Art Gallery, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 3)
    448.2
  - Grant Application-Familiar Problems of Mother in a New Town, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    445.2
    - Letter: Mary Dublin Keyserling to Jane G. Wilhelm, October 26, 1967; 1.
  - Grant Application-Reston Demonstration: Community Approach to Child Care, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    445.3
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    445.5
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Low Cost Housing Research Project, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    445.6
    - Memorandum: Linsenmeyer, J.C. to Board of Trustees, Reston Foundation re: HUD Low Cost Housing Research Project, December 1, 1967; 1.
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD)/Reston Housing Study-Phase Two Report, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    445.7
  - LAX Plywood Tree House and Other Play Equipment, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    445.11
  - Master Plan for Reston, Virginia Submitted to Fairfax County Planning Commission, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    446.13
    - Master Plans for Reston, Va. submitted, March 15, 1962; 1.
    - Press Release: Safire Public Relations, "Master plans for Reston, VA submitted to Fairfax County Planning Commission", March 15, 1962; 2.
  - "New Town: Prospects and Problems" by Robert E. Simon, Jr., 1960s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    446.15
    - New Towns: Prospects and Problems, 1960s?; 1.
    - Paper: Robert E. Simon, "New Towns: Prospects and Problems", early-1960s; 2.
  - Option Agreement-Palindrome Corporation and Carol Lubin, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    446.18
  - Plan for a Democratic School for Inspectors, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Planning Memoranda on Reston-Report to Simon Enterprises, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    447.1
    - Memorandum: Arthur D. Little, Inc., January 1962; 1.
    - Memorandum: Arthur D. Little, Inc. (#2), January 1962; 2.
  - Proposed Children's Center, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 15)
    444.9
  - Report Accompanying the Preliminary Master Plan for Reston, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    447.16
    - Report: Safire Public Relations, Inc, October 3, 1961; 1.
  - Report to Reston, Virginia Incorporated, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    447.17
    - Letter: Robert E. Simon, Jr. to the Stockholders of Reston, VA, Inc., January 1966; 1.
    - Report: George M. Sachs and Company, "Report to Reston, VA, Inc. (name changed from Palindrome Corporation)", September 30, 1965; 2.
  - Reston Day Care Center, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    448.5
  - Reston Low Income Housing Demonstration Program, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    445.13
    - Report: Norman Rowland, Reston Low Income Housing Demonstration Program, April 1969; 1.
  - Reston Outline, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    448.11
  - Reston Outline, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    448.12
  - Reston Studies Working Paper No. 9 Tables Developed for Reston Market Potential Studies, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    448.13
  - Simon Enterprises, Developers Reston, Virginia, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    448.1
    - Reston, Virginia (Planning Report), May 1962; 1.
  - Some Proposals for Research in Reston, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    447.14
    - Paper: Herbert Gans, "Some Proposals for Research in Reston", June 22, 1963; 1.
  - The Reston Community-Fairfax County Revenue and Expense Analysis, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    447.18
- Series 3: International, 1965-1976; (2 boxes)
  he papers in this series are from different planned communities around the world. Most of the papers relate to Israel with additional information from Poland, Great Britain and Japan.
  - Lubin Trips to Israel, Finland, Denmark, Poland and Switzerland, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    447.8
  - England-Public Housing, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Israel-A Tour Guide, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Israel-Address by David Horowitz (Bank of Israel Governor), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Israel-Addresses, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Israel-Agriculture Report, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural and Rural Development in Israel, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Israel-Arad Development Project, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    449.1
    - Report: State of Israel Ministry of Housing, Arad Development Project, ca. 1966; 1.
  - Israel-Building Centre, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Israel-Department of Social Welfare, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Israel-Department of Social Welfare, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Israel-Department of Social Welfare, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Israel-Department of Social Welfare, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Israel-Development, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Israel-Development of Negev Towns, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 21)
    449.2
  - Israel-First World Congress of Engineers and Architects, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Israel-First World Congress of Engineers and Architects, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Israel-First World Congress of Engineers and Architects, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    449.3
  - Israel-First World Congress of Engineers and Architects-Development Patterns in Emerging Countries, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    449.4
  - Israel-First World Congress of Engineers and Architects-Housing and Architecture, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    449.5
    - Presentation: Abba Elhanani, Architectural Problems of Large Scale Building, 1967; 1.
    - Presentation: Pierre Drouin, Art and Science of Urban Renovation, 1967; 2.
  - Israel-Hebrew University-Excavations, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Israel-Housing for Integration, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Israel-Jaffa Community, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Israel-Jerusalem, The Southern Project, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Israel-Kibbutz Gezer, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Israel-Map, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Israel-Maps, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Israel-Mental Health, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Israel-Moshav Settlement, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    449.7
    - Article: Raanan Wietz, "Integrative Planning for Israel's Rural Cooperatives (Moshavim): A New Model", 1975; 1.
    - Booklet: The Jewish Agency Settlement Department, The Moshav in Israel, June 1971; 2.
  - Israel-New Immigrants in Safad, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Israel-New Towns, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 13)
    449.9
  - Israel-Notes, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 14)
    449.10
  - Israel-School Menu, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Israel-Settlement Committee Tour, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    449.12
  - Israel-Social Welfare, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Israel-Social Welfare Law, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Israel-The Arava, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Israel-The Industrial Village, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    449.6
    - Report: Jewish Agency Settlement Department, "The Industrial Village", July 1974; 1.
  - Israel-The Jerusalem Post, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Israel-The Jewish Agency, The Settlement Department, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Israel-The Mountainous Galilee Proposed Plan for Accelerated Development, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    449.8
  - Israel-The Rural Development Program, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    449.11
  - Israel-Twenty Years Housing, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    449.13
  - Poland-Band Shell Architectural Drawings, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 26)
    447.7
  - Poland-Band Shell Architectural Drawings, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 27)
    447.6
  - Poland, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    447.3
  - Poland, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    447.4
    - Letter: Mrs. Carol R. Lubin to Professor Boleslaw Malisz, October 25, 1966; 1.
  - Poland, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    447.5
  - Japan Travel Bureau (JTB), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series 4: Booklets, 1960-1981; (1 box)
  The information in this series includes office workbooks, Reston manual, promotional pamphlets and other information.
  - A Guide to Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 5)
    445.4
  - CETA Administration manual, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    444.8
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Let There Be Commitment" a Housing, Planning and Development Program for New York City, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    445.12
  - Manpower Report, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - More Than Shelter, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Towns, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    446.10
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Proposed Schematic Designs, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 12)
    446.1
    - Office Workbook Designs: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Construction Industry Contacts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 13)
    446.2
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Development of Contacts, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 14)
    446.3
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 15)
    445.14
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Introduction, Sections of Activity, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 16)
    445.15
    - Office Workbook Introduction: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Consultants, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 17)
    445.16
    - Office Workbook Consultants: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Work Program and Schedule, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 18)
    445.17
    - Office Workbook Work Program and Schedule: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Building and Constraints, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 19)
    445.18
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Land Development Costs, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 20)
    445.19
    - Office Workbook Land Development Costs: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, market Analysis, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    445.20
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Mobile Home Industry, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 22)
    445.21
    - Office Workbook Mobile Home Industries: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Alternative Construction Methods, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 23)
    445.22
    - Office Workbook Alternate Construction Methods: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, Environmental Design Team, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 24)
    445.23
    - Office Workbook Environment Design Team: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Office Workbook, Low Income Housing Demonstration, Reston, Virginia, F.H.A. Low Income Minimum Property Standards Study, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 25)
    445.24
    - Office Workbook F.H.A. Low Income Standards: Norman Rowland, ca. 1969; 1.
  - Our People and Their Cities, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    446.20
    - Book: Frederick A. Gutheim, "Our People and Their Cities: A Background to Urban America's Conference to Improve the Quality of Urban America", September 11-13, 1966; 1.
  - Play Sculptures, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 2)
    447.2
  - Presentation Kit-Reston, Virginia, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    447.10
  - Promotional Material, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    447.13
  - Quayside House-Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    447.15
  - Reston at a Glance, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    448.3
  - Reston Manual, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    448.10
    - Reston Manual, ca. 1964; 1.
  - Reston North Golf Course, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 8)
    444.20
  - Technical-Resource Base (Washington), 1963 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Citizen and the Parks, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    444.10
  - The Needs of New communities, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    446.11
  - Urban Land, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    448.18
- Series 5: General Information, 1962-1971; (1.5 boxes)
  The papers cover a variety of topics related to Dr. Lubin's career in Reston. Among the papers are addresses, maps, notes, press releases, newspaper articles and other papers.
  - Addresses-Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 13)
    444.1
  - Addresses-Reston, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 14)
    444.2
  - Article, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Reston, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    444.4
    - Article: Anonymous; "New Towns: Shape of Utopia?"; Newsweek, November 23, 1964; 1.
    - Article: Anonymous; "Reston: An Answer to Suburban Sprawl, Urban Living in the Country," Architectural Record, July 1964; 2.
    - Article: Reston: The New Town Planned to Stop Urban Sprawl, Anonymous, January 28, 1965; 3.
    - Article: Wolf Von Eckardt, "America Tomorrow: Creating the Great Society," The New Republic, 7 November 1964; 4.
    - Press Reports: Reston and House and Home, February 1964; 5.
    - Report: Edward Carpenter, "Brave New Town", Industrial Design, March 1964; 6.
    - Report: House and Home, Editorial, "New Towns for America", February 1964; 7.
    - Report: Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, January 1965; 8.
  - Articles on Reston, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    444.3
    - Article: Anonymous; "The Reston, Virginia Story," Washington World, 17 August 1964; 1.
    - Article: Anonymous; "Reston Industry: Progress Report," Washington World, October 1964; 2.
    - Article: Carl Norcross, "What Buyers Think of Reston," Urban Land: News and Trends in City Development, Volume 25, Number 2, 1965?; 3.
    - Article: Dallas M. Lee, "Planned Communities: Who's Shaping the Future," Home Missions, December 1967; 4.
  - Biographical Material-Carol Lubin, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    446.4
  - Georgetown-East Annapolis, Maryland-Coloring Book, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Introduction to Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    445.8
    - Paper: Anonymous, "Introduction to Reston, Virginia", no date; 1.
  - Lake Anne Center, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 2)
    445.9
    - Community Activities at Reston: Lake Ann Center, November 10, 1965; 1.
  - Lake Anne Nursery-Kindergarten, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    445.10
    - Lake Anne Nursery-Kindergarten, August 11, 1965; 1.
  - Map of Metropolitan Area of Virginia, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    446.7
  - Newsclippings, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    446.14
  - Notes, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 6)
    446.16
  - Notes, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Organizational Chart, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 8)
    446.19
  - Palindrome Corporation-Unanimous Written Consent of Shareholders, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    446.21
    - Palindrome Corporation Unanimous Written Consent of Shareholders (Certificate of Incorporation), 24 May 1965; 1.
  - Payroll, Expenses and Insurance, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    446.5
  - Payroll and Expenses, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    447.12
    - News From Reston, 1967; 1.
    - Press Release: Gulf Oil, Executive Office in Reston, VA, no date; 2.
  - Reston Community Association, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 13)
    448.4
  - Reston Diary, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    448.7
  - Reston, Virginia-Exhibits, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    448.8
  - Reston, Virginia-History, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    448.9
  - Robert H. Ryan, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 17)
    448.15
  - Shotwell Gallery, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Great Powers of the United Nations, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Objectives of the Developer, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 20)
    446.17
    - Reston Virginia: The Objectives of the Developer, no date - 1960s?; 1.
    - Paper: Anonymous, "Reston, VA The Objectives of the Developer", early 1966; 2.
- Series 6: Oversize, 1967-1968; (1 box)
  The series is small and contains information related to Israel. Included in the series are drawings of different planned communities and a book about Israeli development.
  - Israel-Journal of the Association of Engineers and Architects, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    450.1
  - Israel Planned Community Drawing, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 2)
    450.2
  - Israel-Moshav Drawing, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 3)
    450.3
  - Israel-Rehabilitation of the Southern Heights in Ashkelon Pre-Planning Survey, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)